Ammar Bek

Environmental Engineer/Geoscientist

Personal Info

Address

1711-435 Wilson Ave. Kitchener, ON, Canada

N2C 2R9

Phone

519 580 8879

E-mail

ammar.bek79@gmail.com

Skype

Ammar Bek

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ammar-bek

Skills

- Research and development
- Extensive academic knowledge
- Independence and Initiative
- Critical thinking and Problem-solving
- Project Management
- Contributing as a professional
- Attention to details and accuracy
- Interpersonal skills
- IT skills
- Field work skill
- Geophysical instruments operation

Interests

Playing and watching Football

Traveling and Tourism

Photography

Environmental Engineer/Geoscientist with +7 years of experience, has skilled record and proven experience in environmental and geotechnical engineering, engineering geology, geophysics, earthquake engineering, site charactrization and hazard assessment that translated into scientific publications (LinkedIn profile). Seeking to leverage my expertise to fill the advertised position.

Experience

2017-05 -

present

Researcher

University of Waterloo, Civil and Environmental Engineering Department.

- Utilize skills and knowledge to develop new techniques for damage identification in engineering structures.
- Guide a multidiscipline team to finalize research projects.
- Utilize computer skills in modeling, simulation, and data analysis.
- Handle budget, data, and time to execute research projects.

2012-11 -

2017-10

Senior Geophysicist (Full-time)

Amak Geophysical Exploration and Scientific Appliances Company, Iraq

- Created new consulting opportunities by performing high-quality geophysical NDT to solve a environmental and geotechnical problem.
- Enhanced the capacity to perform surveys on noisy and restricted sites.
- Supervised survey projects and survey teams effectively.
- · Actively involved in hazard assessment procedures.
- Performed variety of engineering and environmental field tests.
- Provided full services (processing, interpretation and reporting).
- Prepared training services by conducting seminars and workshops.
- Provided professional consulting and customer services.
- Managed the environmental geophysical dept. starting from June 2016.

2006-10 -

2012-11

Geologist (seasonal and Part-time)

Amak Geophysical Exploration and Scientific Appliances Company, Iraq

- Contributed to establishing the geophysics unit and provided full support.
- Helped to build effective staff by providing suitable scientific training.
- · Conducted field Tests and earth materials sampling.
- Performed Phase I and II Environmental Site Assessments.
- Contributed in interpretation and generating the final report.

Education

Politecnico di Torino, Turin, Italy

Ph.D. in Engineering for Natural and Built Environment, 2012

University of Baghdad, Baghdad, Iraq

MSc in Engineering Geology, 2006

University of Baghdad, Baghdad, Iraq

BSc in Geology, 2002

Software

Microsoft Office MATLAB

Surface Plus WinSism

Seismosoft package EqHaz

QGIS